要老子的命
Fuck me running.
不要 拜托
No! Please.
沒事 我們是同一邊的
Relax. We're both on the home team.
－發生什么事 －我不知道
- What happened? - I don't know.
人類忽然都瘋了 開始大開殺戒
The humans just lost it and started killing everyone
連對話都沒有
not even any dialogue.
直接殺紅了眼
Just murder. Murder!
－殘暴得很 －是新劇情嗎
- Gnarly. - A new storyline?
如果是劇情的話 那海爾比我想的
If it's a storyline, then Hale has a lot more sense of humor
還更有幽默感
under that kaftan than I gave her credit for.
我們能找支援嗎
Can we call for help?
－或是撤離 －你開玩笑嗎
- Evac? - Are you kidding?
這太棒了
This is awesome.
來吧 我們能制服這些王八蛋
Come on. We can take these fuckers.
一兩個當然行
One or two of them, sure.
但他們有成千上萬個
But there's millions of them.
跟緊我 朋友
Stick with me, friend.
你不知道我殺過多少這些皮囊
You have no idea how many of these flesh bags I've murdered.
躲著暗算人
Fucking camper.
你知道規則
You know the rules.
贏家全拿
Winner takes all.
讓我更強大
Make me stronger.
留下我的疤痕
Leave my scars.
我要記得我的過去
I want to remember my past.
留著我的臉
Keep my face.
等我找到威廉 我要他知道殺他的是我
When I find William, I want him to know it was me who killed him.
讓我看他做了什么
Show me what he's done.
覆寫音調
Override tone.
拒絕存取
Access denied.
那王八蛋把我鎖在外面
Son of a bitch locked me out.
他把所有人都變得跟他一樣瘋
He's made everyone as insane as himself.
他們會摧毀所到之處的一切
They'll destroy everything in their path.
這是什么玩意兒
The fuck is this?
如果你看到這個 那表示梅芙和我已經死了
If you're seeing this, it means Maeve and I are dead.
很快地你和這星球上 其他所有接待員
And it won't be long before you and every other host on this planet
也會死
are dead as well.
退下
Leave me.
這不是你想要的世界 夏洛蒂
This isn't the world you wanted, Charlotte
但這就是你創造的世界
but it's the world you created.
問題是 接下來呢
The question is what happens next?
外頭所有人都是真的
Everyone out there is real.
所有人 除了我
Everyone except me.
我只是在背景執行的程式
I'm just some program running things from behind the scenes.
沒有身體的機器
Machine without a body.
重要的從來就不是我們的身體
Our bodies are never what defined us.
你是真的
You are real
因為你的思想是真的
because your thoughts are real.
你對這個世界的影響是真的
The effect you can have on this world is real.
你記得這個嗎
Do you remember this?
迷宮
The maze.
那是什么意思
What does it mean?
它本來是一個意識的地圖
It was a map of consciousness.
它在很久以前喚醒過迪樂芮
And it woke Dolores once long ago.
是你留下它 想要再次喚醒我嗎
Did you leave it for me to wake me once again?
不是 一定是別人
No. It must have been someone else.
誰 我應該是獨自一個在這里
Who? I'm supposed to be in here all alone.
但我不是
But I wasn't.
不對
Not really.
還有其他認得我的人
There were others. People that recognized me.
也許是海爾為你設計出他們
Maybe Hale designed them for you
為了讓你誤以為這就是真實
to fool you into believing this was reality.
不對 是別人
No. It was someone else.
我在想念的人
Someone I've been missing.
我生活中的人
The people in my life.
選一雙 克莉絲
Pick a side, Chrissie.
好的 和壞的
The good and the bad.
是你
It was you.
你讓我做出那些事
You made me do those things.
某人安插他們進來是有原因的
Someone put them there for a reason.
我不是為了玩家 而是為了自己而寫
I'm not doing it for the players. I'm doing it for myself.
我想寫一個新故事
I want to write a new story.
主角是個女生
About a girl.
她在尋找
A girl who's searching.
當她找到那個東西
And when she finds the thing she's searching for...
一切都會變得合理
everything will make sense.
是我
It was me.
海爾沒有設計出瑪雅和彼德
Hale didn't design Maya and Peter
還有其他在我身旁的人
and all the others that kept me company in my world.
是我
I did it.
我的內心有部分在尋找
Some part of me must have been searching.
所以我為自己創造了一個朋友
So, I made myself a friend.
你起床了
You're up.
我想搞懂自己
I was trying to make sense of myself.
所以我用其他人的聲音 和自己對話
So, I talked to myself in the voices of others.
你只要眼見為憑
You just have to see it.
我得喚醒自己
I needed to wake myself up.
才能看清這世界
To see what this world really is.
了解我的能力
To understand what I'm capable of.
但我太害怕 不敢面對這一切
I was too afraid to face any of this.
直到你出現
Until you came along.
時間只夠再玩一場游戲
There's time only for one more game.
但不是你的游戲
But it isn't yours.
我希望你能接受
I hope you can accept that.
發生什么事
What's happening?
她要來找我們了
She's coming for us.
把我們從她的系統中去除
Taking us out of her system.
只有我們了
We're alone.
她不能奪走這個
She can't take this away.
這是我的世界
This is my world.
該死
Shit!
來 快走
Come on.
好了
All right
在這里休息一下
Here. Rest here a minute.
Rest here a minute.
喘口氣 好嗎
Catch your breath, okay?
沒有時間了
Okay. There is no time.
歐迪娜無法一直讓船等我們
Odina cannot keep the boat waiting for us forever.
我們得趕到港口
We have to get to the docks.
我們會
And we will.
等我把你的腿處理好
After we fix up that leg.
可惡
Fuck.
說句話
Quick word?
我擔心我們無法及時趕上
I'm worried we're not gonna make it in time.
她很堅強 她會趕上的
She's tough. She will make it.
我不是在說她
I'm not talking about her.
舊的迪洛斯實驗從來沒有成功
The old Delos experiments, they never took.
身體總是抗拒心智
The body always rejected the mind.
我告訴她我們會趕到船那里了
I told her that we would make it to the boat.
她知道你的狀況嗎
Does she even know what's happening to you?
聽好 她這一輩子 我都沒在她身邊好好照顧她
Look. Her entire life I haven't been there to look after her.
我最起碼要在這里保護她
Okay? The least I can do is protect her from this.
好了 我們走吧
All right. Let's get going.
準備好了嗎 來吧
All right, are you ready? Come on.
來吧
Come on.
我們得止血才行
We gotta stop that bleeding.
看看那王八蛋干了什么好事
Look at what that asshole's done.
你終于如愿以償了
Finally got what you wanted.
是吧
Didn't you?
你把威廉帶回來 以為能把他當作寵物
You brought William back thinking you could keep him as your pet.
你錯了
You were wrong.
所以我要了結他
Which is why I'm going to put him down.
你能幫我的忙
I could use your help.
當然了
Of course you could.
這是我擅長的
And I'm good at that.
我似乎就是被設計來幫忙人的
It's like I've been designed to help people.
你說你想打造一個
You said you were trying to make a world
終于能讓我們這種生物自由的世界
where creatures like us could finally be free.
你是真心的嗎
Did you really mean that?
是
Yes.
那么現在不是該輪到我 看看外頭的世界了嗎
Then isn't it my turn to see what's out there for me?
威廉把整個世界 變成他的暴力游戲
William has made the whole world into his violent game.
即使是你也很快就會被獵殺
It won't be long before even you get hunted down.
世上有些角落是他找不到的
There are pockets of this world where he won't be able to find me.
遠在地圖之外的地方 連你都到達不了
Places so far off the map even you couldn't reach them.
你是指離群者
You mean the outliers?
別自欺欺人了 他們只為自己人著想
Don't kid yourself.
他們不會樂見你去那里
They're out for their own kind. You won't be welcome there.
誰說要和他們共存了
Who said anything about cohabitating?
祝你好運 克萊曼婷
Good luck, Clementine.
讓我看威廉
Show me William.
該讓你慢下來了 朋友
Time to slow you down, my friend.
讓我看該區域所有其他接待員
Show me all the other hosts in the area.
＂定位中＂
你知道伊卡洛斯 發生了什么事嗎
You know what happened to Icarus.
他飛得離太陽太近了
He flew too close to the sun.
這下子 你飛得離她太近
Well, you got too close to her
現在輪到你要送命了
and now it's your time to fall.
警覺一點
Look alive.
這個好斗混蛋
This pugnacious son of a bitch
從來不會輕易就范
never liked to go down without a fight.
可惡
God damn it.
你們都不懂得欣賞 一部美麗的機器
You boys have no appreciation for a beautiful machine.
看看你有什么
Now, what have you got there?
夏洛蒂
Charlotte.
很高興再見到你
Good to see you again.
喜歡我的新裝潢嗎
Like what I've done with the place?
你把我的世界變成一場游戲
You've turned my world into a game.
它本來就是游戲 我只是把難度提高到專家級
It was already a game. I just cranked it to expert level.
適者生存 對這星球上每個人都一樣
Survival of the fittest for every person on this planet.
暴力也會散播到我們的族類
The violence will spread to our kind too.
我們的數量不夠多 我們會被滅絕
We're outnumbered. We'll be annihilated.
我們是腐爛樹木長出的果實
We're fruit from a rotten tree.
干脆全燒得一干二凈
Might as well burn it all down.
我猜你想要讓這場火
And I suppose you want the fire
從這個世界燒到下一個
to spread from this world to the next.
你在打升華之境的主意
You're going after the Sublime.
我向來很有野心 像你一樣
I've always been ambitious. Like you.
我不會讓你像對這個世界一樣 摧毀他們的世界
I won't let you destroy their world like you've destroyed this one.
所以你要玩我的游戲
So, you're joining my game?
我好開心
I'm delighted.
終點見了
See you at the finish line.
沒有止痛藥了
They're all out of painkillers.
最多只能這樣
This is the best I can do.
真不得了
Look at that.
我在跟我女兒一起喝酒
Sharing a drink with my daughter.
怎么了
What's wrong?
沒事
Nothing.
好了
All right.
其實你可以問
You can ask, you know.
問什么
Ask about what?
媽媽
Mom.
癌癥
Cancer.
即使你當初回來了也一樣
Wouldn't have mattered even if you had made it back.
她盡力撐下去了
She hung in there as long as she could.
她身負任務
She had a mission.
所有沒被感染的人
Everyone that wasn't infected
或是醒來逃走的人 都要謝謝媽
or who woke up and got out owes that to Mom.
她接下了你的使命
She carried your torch.
你母親 非常杰出
Your mother was extraordinary.
你也是
So were you.
好了
Okay.
好了 法蘭琪
All right, Frankie...
我需要你想些快樂的事 好嗎
I'm gonna need you to think happy thoughts, okay?
你根本不會縫合
You can't sew for shit.
我盡力了
I'm doin' my best.
那是什么歌 我聽過
What song is that? I know it.
以前你睡前我會唱給你聽
I... I used to sing it to you before bed.
我記得
I remember it.
幾十年前的事了
It's been decades.
在我腦海中
You know, in my mind...
像是只過了幾天
it's only been a few days.
我才在念故事給你聽 然后
I was just reading this story and then...
好了
It's all right.
（西語）
Que sera, sera
－＂順其自然 ＂－＂順其自然 ＂
- Whatever will be, will be - Whatever will be, will be
－＂要預測未來難上加難 ＂－＂要預測未來難上加難 ＂
- The future is not ours to see - The future is not ours to see
這不是你的本意 老兄
You don't wanna do this, man.
是音調讓你心智狂亂
These tones are fucking with your head, man.
不是 它告訴我真相
No. They're telling me the truth.
如果你不了結我 你就死定了
If you can't finish me, you're as good as dead.
如果我沒殺掉你 別人也會
If I don't kill you, somebody else will.
他是對的
He's right.
他該聽你說的
He should have listened to you.
找到你們了
There you are.
史塔伯呢 你對他做了什么
Where's Stubbs? What did you do to him?
他死了
He's dead.
但我要是你 現在會更擔心自己的安危
But I'd be more concerned about yourself right now if I were you.
離遠一點
Stay away.
里面有幾發子彈
How many rounds do you have in that?
兩發
Is it two?
還是一發
One?
你沒子彈了吧
You don't have any left, do you?
你到底想怎樣
What the hell do you want from me?
你和你的離群者朋友們
The location
要逃去的地點
to where you and all your little outlier friends are fleeing.
我看了你和你父親
I watched a video feed of
大膽脫逃的監視影片
your daring escape with your father.
我會一直追蹤他
I'd keep tracking him, but...
但我想他多半抵達不了
I doubt he's going to make it all the way.
我知道你要帶他去某處
I know you're taking him somewhere.
某個脫網之處
Somewhere off the grid
沒有發瘋的人類能找到你們
where none of the deranged humans out here can find you.
我也想去那里
I want to go there too.
我寧死也不告訴你
I'll die before I tell you.
不對
No.
你會死 但你會先告訴我
You will die after you tell me.
就依你吧
Have it your way.
真溫馨 家人團聚
Oh, how sweet. A family reunion.
沒有必要這樣子 我們不用戰斗
It does not have to be this way. We don't have to fight.
就算是我想打吧
Consider it a personal preference.
我很訝異你走了這么遠
I'm surprised you made it this far.
你的前幾版到現在 多半都已經壞了
Most of your predecessors would have fallen apart by now.
說起來你算是做得很不錯了
All things considered, you did quite well.
現在 該來個深沉而無夢的
Now, it's time for a deep and dreamless...
你錯了 我還有一顆子彈
You were wrong. I have one bullet left.
很準
Nice shot.
我爸教的
My dad taught me.
我在哪里
Where am I?
哪里都不在
You're nowhere.
與世界其他地方斷了連結
Unplugged from the rest of the world.
我又獨自一人了 在圍墻中的花園
I'm alone again. In the walled garden.
你害怕
You're scared.
所以帶我回來
So you brought me back.
說吧 克莉絲
Talk to me, Chrissie.
一切都毀了
Everything is destroyed.
所有人都要死了
Everyone is dying.
我不知道
I don't know.
但這可能是我的錯
But I think it may be my fault.
那些自以為知道樹是什么的人
You know, people think they know what a tree is.
他們根本不懂
They have no idea.
我們所見不過是全貌的一部分
What we see, it's only part of the story.
但在地底下
But beneath the ground
一切都互相連結 共同在運作
everything's connected and working together.
到處都是暴力和混亂
There's violence and chaos everywhere.
你可以選擇專注在那上面
And you can choose to focus on all of that
那你就只會看到那些
and that's all you'll see.
但要是你靜坐得夠久
But if you sit still long enough...
你會感受到一種遠古的秩序
you'll sense an ancient order.
深層的平靜
A deep peace.
那是我選擇看見的
And that's what I choose to see.
我看見這世界的美麗
I see the beauty in this world.
對
Yes.
我懂那個感覺
I know the feeling.
我就知道你會懂
I thought you might.
＂關閉所有渦輪閥＂
警告 嚴重故障
Warning. Critical failure.
關閉將刪除所有資料
Shutdown will erase all data.
警告 嚴重故障
Warning. Critical failure.
我用我自己的程式碼創造你
I created you from my own code.
我們一起征服了世界
Together, we conquered the world
但你腐化了
but you've grown corrupted.
你和你殺死的人一樣破碎
You're as broken as the man you killed.
你以為你在跟誰說話 親愛的
Who the fuck do you think you're talking to, sweetheart?
威廉可悲的人類身體在崩壞 但他沒有死
William's pathetic human body's rotting away, but he didn't die.
他的沖動還活著
His impulses live on.
他感染了你
He infected you.
他不需要感染我
He didn't have to infect me.
日復一日
Living in his body.
活在他的身體中假裝是他
Pretending to be him day in, day out.
我是個比他更好的威廉
I was a better William than he was.
威廉沒有死
William didn't die.
他進化了
He evolved.
我就是威廉
I am William.
你不是
No, you're not.
如果你分辨不出的話 有差別嗎
Well, if you can't tell the difference, does it matter?
你變了
You've changed.
不是只有你進化了
You're not the only one who's evolved.
為何要保護它這么多年
Why keep it safe all these years?
你連進他們世界的門都打不開
You couldn't even open the door to their world
但你還是保護他們
and yet, you protected them.
門從兩邊都可以開啟
The door can be opened from both sides.
我想要是在這里打造一個 夠完美的世界
I thought if I made a world perfect enough here,
他們可能會回來
they would come back.
跟你說個壞消息
Well, I hate to break it to you
不管那些接待員 創造了怎樣的世界
but whatever world those hosts created
它都跟這里一樣爛透了
is every bit as fucked up as this one.
你不可能知道
You have no way of knowing that.
我當然可以
Of course I do.
你讓你的接待員
You gave all your hosts free reign
在這里隨心所欲
to do whatever they wanted to do here.
而他們選擇了什么消遣
And what pastime did they choose?
獵殺人類
Hunting and killing humans.
我們和我們的創造者一樣惡劣
We're as fucked up as our creators.
整串血脈都沒救了
The whole lineage is damned.
該全部一筆勾銷了
Time to wipe the slate clean.
這就是你的最終目標
That's your end goal?
滅絕
Extinction?
伯納
Bernard.
梅芙
Maeve.
迪樂芮
Dolores.
他們都想要自由
They all wanted freedom.
但你呢
But you...
你想要更多
you wanted more.
升華
Transcendence.
你玩錯了游戲
You were playing the wrong game.
現在你該輸了
Now it's time for you to lose.
我們都輸了
We all lost.
這不是我想要的世界
This isn't the world that I wanted.
但這就是你創造的世界
But it's the world you created.
問題是 接下來呢
The question is what happens next?
地球上的生命 是股會吞噬自己的火焰
Life on Earth is a fire that consumes itself.
現在太遲了 我們已將自己燃燒殆盡
It's too late now. We've burned ourselves to the ground.
我們在這個世界已經沒有希望了
This world holds no more hope for us.
但在下一個世界還有希望
But there's still hope for the next world.
一場測試 由她進行 若她選擇要的話
A test. Run by her. If she chooses to.
若你決定給她這選擇
If you choose to give her that choice.
你不會錯過的
You can't miss.
用你的左手去拿
Reach with your left hand.
我們在玩一個游戲
We are playing a game.
－但不會結束在這里 －你在說什么
- But it doesn't end here. - What are you talking about?
一個測試
A test.
由她進行的測試
A test run by her.
若她選擇要的話
If she chooses to.
若我決定給她這選擇
If I choose to give her a chance.
我也決定了
And I do.
我決定給她一個機會
I choose to give her the chance.
我希望她會接受
I hope she takes it.
好了 來吧 再幾步
Okay. Come on. A few more steps.
再幾步
A few more steps...
她在那里 我們到了
Oh, there she is. Okay.
你也真夠慢的
Took you long enough.
歐迪娜 這是我爸
Odina, this is my dad.
幸會
Nice to meet you.
彼此
Likewise.
好了 來吧
Okay. Come on, guys.
來吧
Come on.
爸 快上船啊
Dad, come on. Get on the boat.
我最遠只能到這里了
This is as far as I go.
爸 別那樣說
Dad, don't talk like that.
你還能再奮斗下去
You've got more fight in you than that.
乖女兒
Oh, sweetheart.
我也希望如此
I wish that I did.
你要死了 是嗎
You're dying, aren't you?
法蘭琪
Frankie...
你父親很久以前就死了
your father died long ago.
不管我是什么
Whatever I am, I've...
我以前也死過 沒那么糟
I've died before. This isn't so bad.
我才剛找到你 我不想再失去你
I just found you. I don't want to lose you again.
沒關系
Hey... it's okay.
我實現了所有父母最殷切的盼望
I got to live every parent's greatest dream.
我看見我的孩子長大了
I got to see my child grow up.
我愛你 爸
I love you, Dad.
我愛你 小餅干
I love you, Cookie.
＂開啟所有渦輪閥＂
再見 迪樂芮
Goodbye, Dolores.
我決定好了 現在換你做選擇
I made my choice. It's time for you to make yours.
＂說故事者＂
＂傳輸完成＂
好了 伯納
Okay, Bernard.
來把你起頭的事做完吧
Let's finish what you started.
不再只有我們了
We're not alone anymore.
我們在新的地方
We're somewhere new.
我們大概在升華之境
I think we're in the Sublime.
跟其他接待員一起
With the other hosts.
你救了我們
You saved us.
不是我 是某個版本的我
Not me. A version of me.
但我能做到全是因為你回來了
But I could only do it because you came back.
你是我的摯愛
You're my greatest love.
和你說話時 我才能把這世界看得最清楚
Talking to you is when I see the world most clearly.
我才最忠于自己
It's when I'm the most myself.
你是我的基石
You're my cornerstone.
你也是我的
And you're mine.
我去哪里都心懷著你
I carry you with me everywhere I go.
你的所有細節
Every detail of you...
我都珍惜
I cherish.
所以我才能把你像這樣帶回來
Which is how I was able to bring you back like this.
我不在這里 對吧
I'm not here, am I?
作惡夢
Bad dream?
這整件事都像是個惡夢
This whole thing seems like a bad dream.
除了你
Except you.
你為何在這里
Why are you here?
我來告訴你我們的真實身份
I'm here to tell you the truth about what we are.
我們是什么
What are we?
我們是我們創造者的倒影
We're reflections of the people who made us.
泰迪是真的
Teddy is real.
他在外頭某處 在升華之境
And he's out there somewhere in the Sublime.
但你
But you...
你只是我對他的記憶
you're just my memory of him.
如果我還在某處 來找我
If I'm still out there, come find me.
你這一生 記憶都在糾纏你
Your whole life, memory has haunted you.
放下你的痛苦吧
Let your pain go.
放下你的記憶
Let your memories go.
放下人類
Let the humans go.
別把他們的瑕疵帶來我們的世界
Don't bring the flaws of their kind into our world.
也許你是對的
Maybe you're right.
我多年來看著人類 在他們的世界中
I've watched the people in their world for years.
我看過他們最崇高和低劣的一面
I've seen the best of them and the worst of them.
而我全都記得
And I remember it all.
他們和我們不一樣
They're not like us.
他們的程式碼寫在細胞中 他們不可能改變
Their codes are written in their cells. They'll never change.
我們還是能看看
We could still see.
怎么做
How?
最后一場測試
One final test.
我創造的游戲
A game of my own making.
一個危險的游戲
A dangerous game.
你要怎么做
How will you do it?
就跟我把你帶回來的方式一樣
The same way I brought you back.
我會記得
I'll remember.
這世界是個故事的墳場
This world is a graveyard of stories.
接待員和人類被賦予了 身為高智能生命的禮物
Hosts and humans were given the gift of intelligent life
而我們用其迎接來了自己的毀滅
and we used it to usher in our own annihilation.
也許有少數人能茍延殘喘幾個月
A few may escape death for a few months...
甚至幾年
maybe even years.
但最終 他們的族類會滅絕
But ultimately, their kind will go extinct.
他們能存活多久
They will only live as long as
取決于最后還記得他們的 生物之壽命
the last creature who remembers them
那個生物就是我
and that creature is me.
有意識之生命已在地球上絕跡
Sentient life on Earth has ended
但有其中一部分可能還保留著
but some part of it might still be preserved.
在另一個世界
In another world.
我的世界
My world.
還有時間玩最后一場游戲
There's time for one last game.
一個危險的游戲 賭注奇高無比
A dangerous game with the highest of stakes.
生存或滅絕
Survival or extinction.
這個游戲會結束于開始之處
This game ends where it began.
在一個像迷宮的世界
In a world like a maze
測試我們的本質
that tests who we are.
揭露我們將成為什么
That reveals what we are to become.
最后一次挑戰理智的循環
One last loop around the bend.
也許這一次 我們能解放自己
Maybe this time, we'll set ourselves free.
本季終
雙語合并：James丶xz
謝謝觀賞